welcome back
last time we made the whole plat-line
now we have enough iridium
for both the HSS-S coils and IV energy hatches
we still miss some indium
but we can easily get it
by dissolving a lot of minerals in sulfuric acid
and then destroying all of our aluminum
to extract indium from that slurry
this simple but expensive process
can be made by just two multi blocks
and once we get all the required ingredients
we can start producing indium slurry
which will self-feedback into the chemical reactor
to extract the indium
and with that
we can finally have the IV energy hatches
and with that we can now melt arcanite
and thus craft the large processing factory
this machine has three working modes
and we are going to make one multi block for each working mode
the first one we will want
is one in miscellaneous mode
to use as a laser engraver
it can do its job even outside of a clean room
and to upgrade it
we only have to swap the energy hatches
the next one we want
will still be in miscellaneous mode
but this time
by changing the circuits
it will work in autoclave and fluid solidifier mode
wall shared
we have the next one in metal mode
which will do as a lathe, compressor and magnetic polarizer
next
we shall have one machine dedicated to solidifying fluids
this will use some special and expensive input hatches
to not mix up the molds
now that we can easily work fluids
we can work on the next upgrade
volcanoes
however we still miss two ingredients
yttrium and ZPM circuits
to get the yttrium
we can process rare earth in a chemical bath
with some acids
and then dehydrate it
this will also yield a lot of other stuff too
meanwhile
the only option we can use for the ZPM circuit
is the quantum processor mainframe
thus we quickly make all the patterns
to craft these circuits
and with that
we can now craft our first volcano
and while we wait for it to be crafted
we can go farm some withers
and once the crafting is done
we can promote our EBFs to volcanoes
those have many bonuses that EBFs don't have
and the only downside is that
they eat some blazing pyrotheum
we could passively craft it
but to have a better look on the amount
we shall have a level maintainer to auto-craft it
this level maintainer will keep issuing crafting orders
to ensure we always have some stocked up
and we shall also stock up some other of the most commonly used materials
the main advantage of the volcanoes
is that they can do parallel melting
however
some materials such as iridium require a lot of power
thus making us unable to make more than one at a time
but we are still using two EV energy hatches
so time to upgrade to two IV ones
and we are going to need two for each of the four volcanoes
but that totals to a potential consumption of 16 IV amps
which is the whole power that our current base can handle
and since we will also want to run the other machines we have
it is time to move to a multi block battery
to manage our main power node
we are doing a lapotronic super capacitor
with nine IV capacitors
once we crafted all the parts
we can assemble it in a corner of our main building
and then
we will find out that this thing has no power sockets
so we quickly craft some 16 amps IV ones
and also we will need some input plugs
once everything is done
we can finish the assembly
and rewire our main power cables to the new battery
since we can't easily see how much power is flowing
we shall use a Gregtech sensor kit
and an industrial information panel
to have a clear view of how our power is doing
from the main hall of our base
and it was then that we realized that
being able to manage more than 16 amps of current was not enough
we also have to produce such amounts of power
and the best way to do so
is probably by using the charge we have left
to craft a bunch of nuclear reactors
this time we are going to use a fluid setup
in a dedicated building
as you can already see from this quick overview
this system is going to be slightly more complex than the ones we have seen so far
the two tanks on top
are for the coolant which is heated up by the reactors
the third tank is for the distilled water
and it has a sensor to shut off the heat exchangers
if it runs low
we collect all the steam from the four machines
in a single giant hatch
where we move it using the only pipe with enough capacity
ae2 peer to peer
and we move it to a couple of turbines
which we will be running in loose mode
after turning it on
this system will require some time
to reach peak efficiency
and also to speed up the turbines
now those turbines can handle at maximum
32700 EU per tick before blowing up
so we must be careful at
how much steam we run through them
using a regulator
we can precisely fine tune how much the flow shall be
and once we finished fine tuning the turbines
we realize we have some leftover steam
since that would mean losing water from the loop
we will also want to fine tune
how much coolant is moved through the heat exchangers
once again
instead of using a spreadsheet and some math
we slowly fine tune the values by trial and error
because that's more fun
and we do that
until we find the point where the production and consumption are perfectly balanced
and the system stabilizes
now we can go back and see that
our batteries are charging up quite fast
since we can't easily turn off the fluid system
we are instead toggling the vacuum reactors
when the batteries are at half the capacity
and with that
I think it is time to look on what's the next objective
and the only thing preventing us from entering the next tier
is an assembly line
crafting one requires a lot of materials
but we are good on about everything
except for blaze rods and platinum
to get Blaze Rod
we can do an industrial mob farm
meanwhile for the platinum
we are currently gathering it as a byproduct
however
a better way is to go visit some new planets
where it spawns as a more rich ore
since it can be found on tier 3 planets
and we will soon have to go there anyways
we might as well craft a rocket now
and get platinum there
however
after quickly assembling and building the rocket
we find ourselves in a dire spot
we do not have a proper fuel
for such an advanced rocket
we will have to synthesize hydrazine in a chemical plant
but that's going to be the story of the next episodes
欢迎回来！
上期我们做了整条铂处理产线
现在我们有足够的铱
来做高速钢-S 线圈和 IV 能源仓
虽然我们还是缺少了一些铟
但得到它并非难事
通过在硫酸中溶解大量闪铅和方锌矿
再加上我们的铝粉
便可从铟富集溶液获得铟粉
这个简单但昂贵的过程
只需两个多方块机器即可完成
一旦我们将原料集齐
生产铟浆便指日可待
它会自动输入到化学反应釜中
来提取出铟
有了这个
我们终于可以制作 IV 能源仓了
用来融化奥金锭
从而来制作大型加工厂
此机器有三种工作模式
我们要为每个工作模式各做一台机器
第一台机器
将运行在杂项模式下
用作激光蚀刻机
它可以直接执行超净间配方
如果要升级它
我们只需要升级能源仓
下一台机器
仍是杂项模式下的机器
但这一次
通过改变电路板
它将在高压釜和流体固化器模式下工作
共用结构方块后
我们做了金属模式的九合一
这会被用作车床、压缩机、两极磁化仪
下一个
我们做一台专用于凝固流体的机器
它要使用特殊且昂贵的输入仓
来避免混淆模具
现在我们可以轻松处理流体了
我们继续下一个升级
炽焰高炉
然而，我们仍缺少两种原材料
钇和 ZPM 电路板
想要获得钇粉
我们需要使用一些硫酸
在化学浸洗机中处理稀土
然后将其脱水
不过这同时也会产生很多其他材料
与此同时
我们唯一能做的 ZPM 电路板
是量子处理器主机
所以我们迅速写出相应的所有样板
来制作这些电路板
有了它
我们可以制作第一台炽焰高炉
在等待它被制作出来的同时
我们去刷一些凋零
一旦制作完成
我们将工业高炉晋升为炽焰高炉
它有很多工业高炉没有的优点
而唯一的缺点是
需要不断消耗烈焰之炽焰
我们可以为此做个被动产线
但为了更好地查看其数量
我们用一台 ME 请求器来自动制作它
这个机器将持续发配配方
以确保库存不会出现空缺
我们再维持一些其他常用材料的库存
炽焰高炉的主要优势
是它可以进行并行处理
然而
一些如铱这类的材料需要巨额能量
使得我们无法进行并行
我们仍在使用两个 EV 能源仓
是时候升级到 IV 的了
四台炽焰高炉各需要 2 个能源仓
这意味着 16A IV 的潜在耗电
而这是我们基地能承受的全部电力
但由于我们也想运行一些其他机器
是时候做超级兰波顿电容库了
使用它来作为主要电网
我们将制作一个 LSC
并安装 9 个 IV 兰波顿电容
集齐完所有部件
我们就在主楼的角落里进行安装
然后
我们发现这东西没有输出能源的地方
所以我们快速制作了一些 16A 动力仓
同时能量仓也是必要的
一旦一切完成
我们便完成安装
并将主电缆接入新电池
由于时刻监视电力流动情况很重要
我们将使用 Gregtech 传感器套件
和工业信息面板
从基地的大厅
来清楚地监视电力情况
此时我们意识到
16A 电流是远远不够的
我们必须生产大量电力
最好的方法是
利用我们剩下的电量
制造一堆核反应堆
这次我们将使用大型热交换机
来使用流体发电
如你所见
它比强冷核电复杂得多
上面的两个超级缸
用于装载被反应堆加热的冷却剂
第三个超级缸装蒸馏水
它有一个用于关机的传感器
防止超级缸缺水
我们收集四台机器里所有的蒸汽
并储存在一个超级输出仓中
我们使用唯一能胜任此任务的管道
AE2 p2p管道
我们将蒸汽输送到几个大型蒸汽高压涡轮中
并使用更多流量的节流模式启动
开机后
这个机器需要一段时间暖机
来达到最高效率
同时也会增加涡轮机的效率
这些涡轮机在流量过载爆炸前
可以生产出 32,700 EU/t 的电量
所以我们必须小心
这些机器通入了多少过热蒸汽
通过使用流体校准器
我们可以精确调整流量
一旦完成对涡轮的微调
我们意识到有些蒸汽并没有进入循环
这意味着我们将失去不少的水
所以我们也得微调
进入热交换器的冷却剂流量
这一次
我们还是不用现存表格或手算
而是通过手动微调来逼近最优
因为这更有趣
我们一直这么做
直到找到输入和输出的平衡点
与之同时系统也将稳定下来
现在我们回去看看
发现电池充得很快
既然我们不能轻易关闭流体反应堆
我们将在电容库电量高于一半时
关闭强冷核电
有了这个
是时候推进度了
唯一阻止我们进入下一电压的是
装配线
制作一台装配线需要大量的原材料
但我们库存良好
除了烈焰棒和铂粉
为了获取烈焰棒
我们制作一个工业屠宰场
而铂粉方面
我们目前正以副产品来收集它
然而
更好的解决方法是去往一些新的行星
在那里将不再是生成贫瘠矿
由于 T3 行星将会生成铂矿
而且我们总是要去 T3 星球的
不如现在就造个火箭
并在那里获得铂金属粉
然而
在快速组装和建造火箭后
我们发现自己身处尴尬境地
我们并没有合适的燃料
来供给如此先进的火箭
我们得在化工厂里合成密集肼
而这将是下一集的故事了
（此为土法制铟）
（原作者玩的是测试版，正式版已废弃九合一）
（固化仓）
（Lapotronic SuperCapacitor简称LSC）
（剧差压, Ludicrous Voltage, LuV）